C'mon, Vámonos!
Dora and the Search for Sol Dorado is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Alberto Belli.
Dora, Diego, and their new friends trek through the perilous dangers of the Amazonian jungle in
search of the ancient and powerful treasure of Sol Dorado to keep it out of enemy hands.
Dora, played by Samantha Lorraine.
Diego, played by Jacob Rodriguez.
Naiya, played by Mariana Garzón Toro.
Sonny, played by Acston Luca Porto.
Beetle, played by Christian Gnecco Quintero.
Boots (voice), played by Gabriel Iglesias.
Dora and the Search for Sol Dorado is a 2025 American action comedy adventure
film directed by Alberto Belli and written by JT Billings.
The film is loosely based on the Dora the Explorer franchise, and stars Samantha Lorraine, Jacob Rodriguez, Mariana
Garzón Toro, Acston Luca Porto, Christian Gnecco Quintero, Gabriel Iglesias, and Daniella Pineda.
It recreates the characters and reboots the story of an explorer named Dora and her cousin Diego, who are in search of
an ancient magical fallen star through a jungle, while facing an archaeologist with the similar mission.
After about two years of development, the film production took place across locations in Colombia,
including jungle, theme parks, and a studio, during the summer and fall of 2024.
The film was released simultaneously on Paramount+ and Nickelodeon
on July 2, 2025, to generally positive reviews.
The film explores themes of based on cartoon, children's
adventure, based on tv series, exciting, brisk.
The tone is lighthearted.